<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IT circle of Ascol on Open Source Ascol Circle</title><link>https://osac.org.np/</link><description>Recent content in IT circle of Ascol on Open Source Ascol Circle</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osac.org.np/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OSAC Mapathon OpenStreetmaps 2022</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-2022/</guid><description>The event &amp;ldquo;Mapathon&amp;rdquo; is concluded successfully. More than 40 students actively participated in this event. These are some of the glimpses of the event &amp;ldquo;Mapathon&amp;rdquo;.
We thank Miss Sushma Ghimire for mentoring throughout this session.
Thanks Geomatics Engineering Society for helping with the project.
Also huge thanks to Open Mapping Hub - Asia Pacific for supporting this session.
Also kudos to every OSAC Executives and participants for making this session happen.</description></item><item><title>OSAC Mapathon Pre-Event 2022</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-pre-event-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-pre-event-2022/</guid><description>Unknown to Openstreetmap but still want to participate in OSAC Mapathon??? We got you covered. We are coming with pre event session to teach you about Openstreetmap. This session will be held on OSAC&amp;rsquo;s discord server and will be facilitated by Miss Sushma Ghimire, 6PM onwards at 27 Jan 2023 .
Here is the invitation link to the server : https://discord.gg/63ButMqj. Or you can scan QR in the image banner.</description></item><item><title>Mapping on OSM 2022</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/mapping-on-osm-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/mapping-on-osm-2022/</guid><description>The event &amp;ldquo;Mapping in OSM&amp;rdquo; is concluded finally. More than 40 students participated in this event. Most of the participants were new to OpenStreetMap. In this event, we learnt about OpenStreetMap and its use case in various areas, we also learnt how to do mapping and editing in OpenStreetMap. The quiz session at last added more fun in this learning process. Happy mapping to all the participants. We thank Miss Sushma Ghimire for mentoring throughout this session.</description></item><item><title>Python Webscraping Workshop 2022</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/python-webscraping-workshop-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/python-webscraping-workshop-2022/</guid><description>A 3 hour long workshop on python webscraping techniques conducted by KU and OSAC.
Event Gallery</description></item><item><title>OSM hackfest Pre-Event 2022</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osm-hackfest-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osm-hackfest-2022/</guid><description>A pre-event program conducted with collaboration with Open Tech Community and OSAC regarding taking part in Open Street Map hackfest.
Events: Open Data, OpenStreetMap, Free &amp;amp; Open Source Software
Event Gallery</description></item><item><title>GitHub Intro Session</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/github-intro-session-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/github-intro-session-2022/</guid><description>Online introductory session on github, navigating the website, usecases and usage demonstration on creating repository, forking and contribution with pull requests, creating issues.</description></item><item><title>IT circle of Ascol</title><link>https://osac.org.np/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/about/</guid><description>Who we are? OSAC (Open Source ASCOL Circle) is a group of lerners based primarily on Computer Science and Information Technologies students from Amrit Science College, Tribhuvan University, Nepal.
We LOVE Open Source Softwares/Open Source Philosophy.
What we do? We share our knowledge among friends through formal and informal, regular and occasional get-togethers. In such get-togethers we talk, demonstrate, teach share and learn BUT basically we have fun there.
OSAC on github?</description></item></channel></rss>