<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Open Source Ascol Circle</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Open Source Ascol Circle</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osac.org.np/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Frontend Development Bootcamp</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-week-webdev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-week-webdev/</guid><description>OSAC successfully conducted a 5-day-long Frontend Development Bootcamp featuring Senior Software Engineer Sushant Suwal.
Our speaker, Sushant Suwal, mentored participants in the Bootcamp for 4 days, following a structured roadmap. He provided insights into the field of frontend development and guided participants on how to kickstart their careers in frontend. Throughout the 5-day bootcamp, he taught HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and TailwindCSS. The workshop also included a project creation session on the 4th day.</description></item><item><title>Github Essentials</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/introducing-communities-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/introducing-communities-1/</guid><description>OSAC successfully conducted its first event under Introducing Communities &amp;ldquo;Github Essentials&amp;rdquo;. This event focused on essential Github topics such as the Github Field Day, Github Community, and the Github Developer Pack. The session provided an in-depth understanding of these initiatives.
Our speaker, Yunika Bajracharya being one of Github Campus Expert , provided detailed tips and insights, sharing her expertise on the steps and strategies required to required to get into these things.</description></item><item><title>OSAC Figma and Photoshop Workshop 2024</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-figma-photoshop-workshop-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-figma-photoshop-workshop-2024/</guid><description>OSAC successfully conducted its first event for August as part of OSAC Week - the &amp;ldquo;Figma and Photoshop Workshop - Online Design Bootcamp&amp;rdquo;. This event marked the beginning of our initiative to host monthly 2-5 day bootcamps, workshops, or webinars on specific tech topics.
The bootcamp covered both theoretical aspects of designing and practical applications. Our talented speaker, Nikki Arts (@nikki_arts__), led an engaging hands-on session, while Anupama Rai (@anupamaa_raii) skillfully moderated the event.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started in App Development with OSM 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-app-development-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-app-development-2023/</guid><description>Learning, exploring and growing together is always so fun and inspiring. We successfully conducted &amp;ldquo;Getting started with App development based on OpenStreetMap&amp;rdquo;. The event was fruitful thanks to the combined effort of OSAC team, our dear mentor Ichchha Moktan and all of the participants.
Ms Ichchha guided us participants how to harness OSM in apps, what specific benefits it provides and answered our queries about specific caveats and usecases. About 40 Participants both from BIT and CSIT were present the event.</description></item><item><title>OSAC OSM Web Development Project Demonstration 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-web-development-project-demonstration-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-web-development-project-demonstration-2023/</guid><description>Some glimpses from final day of Web Development Bootcamp where Mr. Hemanta Mahatara demonstrated his project.
He walked us throught the django + leaflet web project he had built and explained the challenges, ways one can go abou making such project.
We thank Mr. Hemanta Mahatara and everyone who participated in this session.
Event Archive View youtube recording Event Gallery</description></item><item><title>OSAC OSM Web Development BootCamp 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-web-development-bootcamp-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-web-development-bootcamp-2023/</guid><description>An event must have interested participants to be called successful and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more proud to have more than 50 participants in our event &amp;ldquo;Web development bootcamp using Leaflet Library&amp;rdquo;.
It was also an orientation to our amazing juniors about our club and their active participation have encouraged us to push our limits in future. Hence, we gladly announce the successful completion of 2-days event amongst the 3 days and hope to have the same numbers tomorrow on virtual session as well.</description></item><item><title>OSAC Mapathon OpenStreetmaps 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-2023/</guid><description>The event &amp;ldquo;Mapathon&amp;rdquo; is concluded successfully. More than 40 students actively participated in this event. These are some of the glimpses of the event &amp;ldquo;Mapathon&amp;rdquo;.
We thank Miss Sushma Ghimire for mentoring throughout this session.
Thanks Geomatics Engineering Society for helping with the project.
Also huge thanks to Open Mapping Hub - Asia Pacific for supporting this session.
Also kudos to every OSAC Executives and participants for making this session happen.</description></item><item><title>OSAC Mapathon Pre-Event 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-pre-event-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-pre-event-2023/</guid><description>Unknown to Openstreetmap but still want to participate in OSAC Mapathon??? We got you covered. We are coming with pre event session to teach you about Openstreetmap. This session will be held on OSAC&amp;rsquo;s discord server and will be facilitated by Miss Sushma Ghimire, 6PM onwards at 27 Jan 2023 .
Here is the invitation link to the server : https://discord.gg/63ButMqj. Or you can scan QR in the image banner.</description></item><item><title>Mapping on OSM 2022</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/mapping-on-osm-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/mapping-on-osm-2022/</guid><description>The event &amp;ldquo;Mapping in OSM&amp;rdquo; is concluded finally. More than 40 students participated in this event. Most of the participants were new to OpenStreetMap. In this event, we learnt about OpenStreetMap and its use case in various areas, we also learnt how to do mapping and editing in OpenStreetMap. The quiz session at last added more fun in this learning process. Happy mapping to all the participants. We thank Miss Sushma Ghimire for mentoring throughout this session.</description></item><item><title>Python Webscraping Workshop 2022</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/python-webscraping-workshop-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/python-webscraping-workshop-2022/</guid><description>A 3 hour long workshop on python webscraping techniques conducted by KU and OSAC.
Event Gallery</description></item><item><title>OSM hackfest Pre-Event 2022</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osm-hackfest-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osm-hackfest-2022/</guid><description>A pre-event program conducted with collaboration with Open Tech Community and OSAC regarding taking part in Open Street Map hackfest.
Events: Open Data, OpenStreetMap, Free &amp;amp; Open Source Software
Event Gallery</description></item><item><title>GitHub Intro Session</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/github-intro-session-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/github-intro-session-2022/</guid><description>Online introductory session on github, navigating the website, usecases and usage demonstration on creating repository, forking and contribution with pull requests, creating issues.</description></item></channel></rss>