<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023 on Open Source Ascol Circle</title><link>https://osac.org.np/tags/2023/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 on Open Source Ascol Circle</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osac.org.np/tags/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started in App Development with OSM 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-app-development-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-app-development-2023/</guid><description>Learning, exploring and growing together is always so fun and inspiring. We successfully conducted &amp;ldquo;Getting started with App development based on OpenStreetMap&amp;rdquo;. The event was fruitful thanks to the combined effort of OSAC team, our dear mentor Ichchha Moktan and all of the participants.
Ms Ichchha guided us participants how to harness OSM in apps, what specific benefits it provides and answered our queries about specific caveats and usecases. About 40 Participants both from BIT and CSIT were present the event.</description></item><item><title>OSAC OSM Web Development Project Demonstration 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-web-development-project-demonstration-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-web-development-project-demonstration-2023/</guid><description>Some glimpses from final day of Web Development Bootcamp where Mr. Hemanta Mahatara demonstrated his project.
He walked us throught the django + leaflet web project he had built and explained the challenges, ways one can go abou making such project.
We thank Mr. Hemanta Mahatara and everyone who participated in this session.
Event Archive View youtube recording Event Gallery</description></item><item><title>OSAC OSM Web Development BootCamp 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-web-development-bootcamp-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-web-development-bootcamp-2023/</guid><description>An event must have interested participants to be called successful and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more proud to have more than 50 participants in our event &amp;ldquo;Web development bootcamp using Leaflet Library&amp;rdquo;.
It was also an orientation to our amazing juniors about our club and their active participation have encouraged us to push our limits in future. Hence, we gladly announce the successful completion of 2-days event amongst the 3 days and hope to have the same numbers tomorrow on virtual session as well.</description></item><item><title>OSAC Mapathon OpenStreetmaps 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-2023/</guid><description>The event &amp;ldquo;Mapathon&amp;rdquo; is concluded successfully. More than 40 students actively participated in this event. These are some of the glimpses of the event &amp;ldquo;Mapathon&amp;rdquo;.
We thank Miss Sushma Ghimire for mentoring throughout this session.
Thanks Geomatics Engineering Society for helping with the project.
Also huge thanks to Open Mapping Hub - Asia Pacific for supporting this session.
Also kudos to every OSAC Executives and participants for making this session happen.</description></item><item><title>OSAC Mapathon Pre-Event 2023</title><link>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-pre-event-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://osac.org.np/post/osac-osm-mapathon-pre-event-2023/</guid><description>Unknown to Openstreetmap but still want to participate in OSAC Mapathon??? We got you covered. We are coming with pre event session to teach you about Openstreetmap. This session will be held on OSAC&amp;rsquo;s discord server and will be facilitated by Miss Sushma Ghimire, 6PM onwards at 27 Jan 2023 .
Here is the invitation link to the server : https://discord.gg/63ButMqj. Or you can scan QR in the image banner.</description></item></channel></rss>